along with the first brain organoid
bioom computers which really are just
tiny human brains grown from stem cells
that can operate and do computation one
of the issues researchers have had to
deal with is communicating with them
effective communication involves
allowing them to grow while they're
being recorded in terms of neural
activity into a computer this group used
these little
electrosensitive cups that monitor
electrical activity and then a computer
can send information back to the brain
organoid giving it either ordered or
unordered signals to tell it if it's
doing a good job in one case researchers
used AI to let it learn human speech and
supervised and it began to not only just
recognize human speech patterns and know
what words were being said but also
recognize the differences between voices
they are extremely effective at doing
this that means your future potentially
conscious robot look we're not there yet
but it could happen may be able to have
real conversations with you more
recently some researchers found that
they train on dopamine very effectively
so while the ordered signals are still
going to be present adding a little hint
to dopamine when they do something right
helps the brain organoid know that
they're doing it so it's a little bit
more than just information that's going
in and out it also seems to be a little
bit of pleasure on their behalf in terms
of decoding what the little brain
organoids are thinking about it's not
all that dissimilar to electrodes that
we use to record human thought and for
human brains we can even take the images
that we're thinking about in our brains
and record them using AI which puts them
into IM
in this way we can even record your
dreams we can also record what the brain
organoids might be doing this technology
is moving so fast and I think we're
going to find a lot more information on
how to grow them effectively and how to
communicate with them